[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 2]
[Shen's Mansion]
Sir,
the grand empress dowager has arranged a marriage for you.
Should we make preparations?
Uncle Zhong,
you don't need to worry about that.
As long as I'm here,
she won't be able to enter the mansion.
Do you plan
to scare her through the ghostly trick
of throwing heads and darts again?
This time, it's a marriage arranged by the grand empress dowager.
Wouldn't it be...
So what?
As usual,
I'll scare her away!
Minister Zhang,
this...
Enough.
Say no more.
Just do as I said.
Dr. Yan,
you're a sensible person.
You surely won't betray
my trust in you.
Rest assured, Minister Zhang.
Close the gate.
Honey.
Minister Zhang came in person.
Why?
Shen Du has always been neutral
in the court.
He's always been like that especially in the competition
between Prince Xian and Princess Ying.
Minister Zhang is Prince Xian's strategist.
He picked Caiwei this time.
Surely it isn't just for her talent.
He wants Caiwei to be a spy?
Lower your voice.
No way.
Caiwei definitely can't marry him.
Minister Zhang just mentioned to me again
about the re-election of the six ministries.
If Caiwei doesn't marry him,
during the re-election,
they'll pick me to garrison the desert.
And our whole family will have to go.
Minister Zhang actually
threatened Father with exiling our whole family to the desert.
Master! Madam!
Bad news!
Lady Caiwei... Lady Caiwei ran away!
She said
she eloped with a scholar
named Han Shiyuan.
[Han Shiyuan is a good husband, and I've left with him.]
[Father, Mr. Han and I love each other, and we've secretly pledged to spend our lives together.]
This rebellious daughter!
Master!
-Honey!
-Father!
-Master!
-Honey!
Father!
Why are you all looking at me?
You've found Caiwei?
If not, hurry up and go look for her!
Even if you have to turn Xiang'an City upside down,
you must bring that rebellious girl
back to me!
Everyone, look for her thoroughly.
Hurry! Go now! Go!
Wait!
Keep it a secret.
We can't let anyone else know
that Caiwei is missing.
That's right.
We can't tell anyone else Caiwei ran away.
Just tell them...
Xing's pet rabbit is missing.
-Yes.
Xing.
You get around often and are familiar
with the surroundings.
You're also close to Caiwei.
Go out and look for her too.
Okay.
Then... I'm going to look for the rabbit as well.
Yan Xing.
Does the Yan family forbid
a concubine's daughter to go home?
Why are you always running around outside?
Grand Commander, please step aside.
My rabbit is missing.
I need to go find it.
Really?
So it's a rabbit that went missing.
Today, the gate
of the Yan family has been closed all day long.
I thought you were
busy preparing for the wedding.
It turns out you closed the gate just to look for a rabbit.
If you've finished mocking me,
I'll go and continue to look for it.
Well, you'd better find it.
Tomorrow is the wedding day
of me and your third sister.
I'm really
looking forward to seeing you
at the wedding with your rabbit.
Grand Commander,
no offense,
but I want to ask you for a favor.
Asking me for a favor?
Apart from the prisoners in jail
who are desperate to die,
I'm afraid
no one else across Cang State
would want to ask me for a favor.
Please break off the engagement with my third sister.
Do you know what you're talking about?
I do.
Grand Commander,
please cancel the marriage arrangement with my third sister.
Although you don't hold an official rank,
you are at least
a literate minor official.
Do you understand that imperial orders
can't be disobeyed?
The grand empress dowager has given the order.
You can't cancel it just because you want to.
The grand empress dowager
favors you a lot.
She naturally wants to arrange
a good marriage for you.
That's right.
The grand empress dowager picked her through careful consideration,
and Minister Zhang has vouched for it.
I believe that your third sister and I
will surely make a good match.
That's because the grand empress dowager
doesn't know what the Yan family's girls
are really like.
As you can see, I'm so vulgar and disrespectful,
so you should know
my third sister and you
would never make a good match.
Are you saying
your third sister's talent and virtues are all a pretense?
If so,
you've committed a crime by deceiving the emperor.
I...
I was talking about myself.
You are indeed vulgar and disrespectful,
but you're not the one I'm about to marry.
I feel sorry for your third sister.
She has such a disrespectful
younger sister.
But you and my third sister
have never met.
Aren't you worried
that you won't love each other
and you'll end up as a resentful couple?
What does it matter?
How can it not matter?
People should be with someone
they love,
treating each other with respect
and cherishing each other.
Only then can they be happy.
It's not important.
You...
You're simply hopeless
and unreasonable!
How dare you!
Shen Du,
even though I didn't want to believe
the rumors about you,
look at how you are now:
harsh in words,
irrational in behavior,
tyrannical,
and unreasonable.
Even if my third sister
doesn't have anyone in her heart,
she would never marry you!
Treat each other with respect
and cherish each other?
Those things
are already too far from me.
Mother,
one day,
I will move you to the noblest
[Bi Luo]
and the most luxurious cemetery in the world,
where you'll receive countless offerings.
[Bi Luo]
My Lord,
everything is ready.
Grand Commander,
Yan Xing's words
may be unpleasant,
but...
you don't want
this marriage either, right?
Since they already asked you to break off the engagement
before we scare her,
why don't you just go along with it?
Of course I can't marry her.
But I can't
be the one to break off the engagement.
That's right.
The grand empress dowager arranged this marriage.
Of course you should be grateful.
We need to make the Yan family
take the initiative to break off the engagement.
According to our men,
Yan Caiwei
eloped with that scholar.
They still haven't found her yet.
Even if they won't break off the engagement,
tomorrow's bride fetching ceremony
will naturally be canceled, right?
They're in the wrong,
so Minister Zhang
will naturally have to explain
to the grand empress dowager.
How can we only watch half of the show?
The bride's whereabouts
is the Yan family's business.
Of course I should
send a team of bridesmaids tomorrow morning
to fetch the bride.
[Wedding]
[Yan's Mansion]
[They left everything behind and eloped before the wedding.]
[But I didn't expect my daughter to have someone she loves.]
[The Yan family should be grateful for the marriage arranged by the grand empress dowager.]
[Wedding]
Everyone,
you have worked in Yan's Mansion for many years.
Now the Yan family is in deep trouble.
I'm afraid the Yan family's doom is fated.
I prepared some money for you all.
Go make a living somewhere else.
I've already made a will.
Mother!
I don't want to die, Mother!
-Mother!
-Forget it.
I'll marry him.
What time is it now?
Why hasn't the bride come out yet?
We're going to miss the auspicious time.
♫I hope you also look up and see the radiant stars and moon♫
♫No matter how vast the world is, I'll wait for your appearance♫
♫A quick glance at each other♫
♫Has warmed the winter in memories♫
♫Don't mind the destined solitude, and shine brightly♫
♫I'll wait until the years blossom like flowers♫
♫The ice and snow slowly melted♫
♫I heard those tender words♫
♫He told her, "I love you"♫
♫What I saw in my dreams♫
♫Is not a flashy illusion♫
♫I don't fear the challenges ahead, riding a white horse to chase after time♫
Xing!
♫Let's go together♫
Xing, you can't do this! Xing!
Xing!
I thought about it. I can't let you do this.
Think about it.
What kind of person is the White Ghost?
He crawled out
of a pile of corpses of the Shen family.
It's not a good thing for you to marry into the Shen family.
Run away now.
Take this.
You have many connections in the Ministry of Justice.
Find a place and hide there
for three months first.
You can come back home
when things calm down.
Don't worry about me.
Your father is just a paper tiger.
He can't do a thing to me.
At worst,
I'll take good care of him for the rest of my life
by serving tea and water and massaging his shoulders and legs.
If it really doesn't work out,
just write a divorce letter
to me.
I'll return to my old profession—
an opera performer.
I can still support us both.
Mother,
which theater
would hire a white-haired performer?
Although I'm a concubine's daughter,
I've been under your protection since childhood
and haven't suffered many hardships.
And Sister Caiwei has been very nice to me.
Back then,
I didn't want to learn needlework
and was determined to become a female official.
It was Sister Caiwei
who knelt in the ancestral hall all night
to plead for me.
You silly girl,
you only remember the kindness of others.
I am a member of the Yan family,
so naturally, I can't
stand by and watch the Yan family suffer.
Sister Caiwei doesn't want to marry him
because she loves Mr. Han.
I have no one in my heart,
so I'll just take her place to marry him.
Silly girl,
getting married isn't that simple.
Mother,
don't worry.
I've seen plenty of dead people
in the Ministry of Justice.
Dealing with
the White Ghost is not a big deal.
Besides,
he's only flesh and blood like us.
He can't really
drag me to the underworld, right?
Alright.
Father,
Madam,
please take good care of my mother for me.
I'm...
leaving now.
[Yan's Mansion]
Escort the bride!
Grand Commander,
before the wedding ceremony,
the bride and the bridegroom shouldn't meet.
Also, lowering the sedan chair midway is ominous.
Besides, as the bridegroom,
why aren't you wearing your wedding attire?
Cut the crap.
The Imperial Security Bureau is here to escort the bride.
So we follow the Imperial Security Bureau's rules.
Whether it's auspicious or not,
it's up to Grand Commander.
This...
My dear wife,
I've come to see you,
a lady from the Yan family
who is famous in Xiang'an
for being knowledgeable and virtuous.
This virtuous lady...
is me.
Grand Commander, do you plan
to kill your wife in public?
Don't forget
our marriage was arranged by the grand empress dowager.
Although I don't have an official rank now,
and I'm not a court-appointed official,
I am at least a scribe in the Ministry of Justice.
This is not a crime scene,
and there's no suspect holding anyone hostage.
Even though you are the grand commander,
you can't just
kill an innocent scribe without a reason.
Is that so?
Since when
does a fly get to be a scribe?
Grand Commander, why do you have to humiliate me like this?
If you're so dissatisfied
with our marriage,
why don't you just kill me now?
Don't worry.
Today, I
have spared your life,
but soon,
I'll make your life a living hell.
Yan Xing is really bold.
She actually has the guts to take her third sister's place to marry you.
She's deceived the empress dowager. And that's a serious crime.
The grand empress dowager only said she arranged a marriage
for me and a daughter of the Yan family.
As for which daughter,
the grand empress dowager doesn't care at all.
But you...
I care even less.
She'll be driven away sooner or later.
The Yan family doesn't have many
interesting rabbits.
The bold one
is more interesting.
This is rare.
She's not just bold.
Looks like she's also clever.
Xing!
Chuichui?
Xing,
it really is you.
I heard
your third sister was getting married today.
I wanted to find you
to join in the fun together.
But
when I arrived at Yan's Mansion,
I saw Ms. Jin crying at the entrance.
She said you're the one who's getting married.
Xing,
are you unwilling?
But isn't the bridegroom
Shen Du?
He's not Shen Du anymore,
but the tyrannical White Ghost.
Don't worry, Chuichui.
Go back.
No.
How can I just watch you fall into the hands
of the White Ghost?
I'm going with you.
We'll
face this together.
This is bad!
What's wrong?
Calm down. Take your time.
The bride is on her way here.
[Shen Zhong, the butler of the Shen family]
The bride?
[Prudence and Reverence]
[Peace and Prosperity]
What special family rules?
Shen's Mansion looks
like a mourning hall.
It doesn't look like a wedding at all.
[Prudence and Reverence]
So many white lanterns.
Madam,
you've just arrived at Shen's Mansion.
We don't dare to be negligent.
Marriage
is all about the right time, place, and people.
[Peace and Prosperity]
A few days ago,
we consulted a master to analyze
the compatibility of your birth charts.
So today, the mansion shouldn't be
decorated with lanterns or streamers.
It's alright.
Mr. Shen, it's up to you.
Please.
[Peace and Prosperity]
The grand commander's central chamber,
due to his long years of solitary living,
lacks auspicious energy.
So it's unsuitable for being a bridal chamber,
as it may invite bloodshed.
We've specially prepared a new room for you.
Please rest early,
and wait for Grand Commander to return from his prayers.
Don't go too far!
It's alright.
Please lead the way.
Please.
Mr. Shen.
I wonder if you remember
what my birth chart is.
Well...
A lady's birth chart
is not something
to be spoken of in public.
Thank you for your thoughtfulness.
Please.
Chuichui,
have some preserved fruit.
You still have an appetite?
-Madam,
-we look forward to hearing the patter of tiny feet.
Now, really?
Did you never truly believe
Xing would marry into this family?
Chuichui,
don't give them a hard time.
They've gone too far.
I'm afraid they all thought
I would run away halfway.
But this is
too insulting.
It's okay.
Just empty formalities.
Empty formalities?
Your family suffered losses in real gifts too.
I heard
the gifts Shen Du delivered to your family
are nothing but showy trinkets.
They're nothing of real value.
This...
This is worse
than marrying into an ordinary family.
At least they'd be sincere.
Usually, the bride's family gets a pair of wild geese for the wedding,
but your family only got a big hen.
How are you still laughing?
Since he doesn't want to marry me,
I insist on marrying him.
[Three]
Grand Commander, bad news!
I've received news from the guards!
That bride is truly something else.
Not only did she not leave,
she actually came back.
Now she's probably in Shen's Mansion already.
Yan Xing is indeed something.
The point is
nobody thought the wedding would
actually happen.
They didn't prepare anything.
But she
went to help with the arrangements.
And now she's even there
giving them advice.
Let her be.
In the past, there were indeed many fearless women
who tried to pester you in order to marry
into the Shen family.
But with just a little bit
of your tricks,
they immediately ran away.
None of them ever dared to enter
the bridal chamber after seeing your sword.
After she entered the mansion,
Mr. Shen deliberately withheld
the betrothal gifts.
Instead of getting angry, she insisted on marrying you.
This woman is well-trained
and faces challenges head-on.
Since Minister Zhang sent her here,
there must be a major conspiracy behind it.
[Lu]
If even you can see through it,
how can it still be called a conspiracy?
The rabbit this time...
is much more interesting
than the previous ones.
Regarding the official matchmakers...
Grand Commander, please rest assured.
I have already warned
the wedding procession.
Now everyone will simply believe the wedding
went smoothly, and the ceremony
has been completed.
Now I understand
why Shen Du is called the White Ghost.
Look at all these.
During the day, it already looked like a mourning hall.
At night,
it's still as bright as daylight.
Is he trying to light up the underworld
and guide the spirits?
I'm afraid it's because he's worried ghosts might knock on his door at midnight
given what he's done all these years.
Xing,
do you really
feel nothing but disgust
for the White Ghost now?
When I was young, I was blind
and thought he was a good man.
After these past few days,
I've seen through him.
Then what about those words he said when he stopped the sedan chair?
He probably didn't want me to enter the mansion.
He was just trying to scare me away.
Then what should you do?
Don't worry.
After all, our marriage
was arranged by the grand empress dowager personally.
He won't do anything
against me for now.
I'll be cautious
and take it one day at a time.
At the very least, I'll hold out
until the court finalizes the list of officials for external assignments,
so that my family
won't be exiled to the desert.
This isn't a marriage.
This is like stepping into a den of demons.
Surviving in the underworld
is not that easy.
It's getting late.
You should go back now.
Or your father will be worried.
I'm not leaving.
I want to stay here with you.
Can you come to keep me company every day?
Don't risk yourself too.
Don't worry.
Tonight,
I'm sure he will put on an air
of indifference and disdain towards me.
He won't come to my chamber.
Why are you here?
This is Shen's Mansion.
Tonight is my wedding night.
Why can't I come?
But look at you.
The Yan family has a daughter,
gifted in poetry and prose,
graceful with brush and ink,
well-versed, virtuous,
and knowledgeable.
Her reputation as a virtuous lady
is unmatched in Xiang'an.
Which
of those descriptions fits you?
We do.
The grand empress dowager must think
that you and I
are a perfect match.
Otherwise, why would she have arranged this marriage?
Grand Commander, if you
are not satisfied with me,
you can just divorce me.
The fanciful thoughts
in your head echo
your pretty face.
You're such a pretty and charming young lady.
I should cherish you dearly.
Why would I easily divorce you?
I've never seen a bride running around the courtyard
before the ceremony is even complete.
If you don't want to accidentally
break a leg or lose an arm
in Shen's Mansion,
remember to behave yourself.
You're right, Honey.
Honey,
since I've accepted the imperial decree,
of course I should fulfill my duty
as Mrs. Shen in Grand Commander's Mansion
and serve you
with utmost care and attention.
You think you can
seduce me like this?
Since you said you want to serve me well,
let me tell you three things.
First,
don't expect to become
the true Mrs. Shen.
We are a couple
in name only.
Second,
don't expect to get
any information from me.
I know why Minister Zhang
sent you here.
Third,
you're not someone
I willingly married.
Don't expect to survive in Shen's Mansion.
Sir,
you've met Madam?
Then the wedding ceremony...
Consider it done.
Then...
the west wing...
Let her stay there.
Grand Commander!
The Ming Hall is on fire.
Hurry up!
Grand Commander.
How did the Ming Hall catch fire?
Someone set himself on fire inside,
which started the blaze.
The person who self-immolated
has been burned beyond recognition.
Immediately dispatch more men to ensure
the security of the imperial palace.
Investigate the identity of the self-immolator thoroughly.
Leave no stone unturned.
Yes.
[Ming Hall]
Why won't you let us meet?
I am a female official from the Ministry of Justice.
Yesterday,
I accompanied her
into the bridal chamber.
Miss, you really can't go in.
Without the steward's order...
Please.
We can't let you in.
That's right.
Chuichui.
You can't go in.
Xing,
something terrible has happened!
-Madam.
Near the bamboo forest of the Ximing Temple,
someone found a pair of bodies.
The bodies look very weird.
The Ministry of Justice and constables
have already sent people there.
Let's go.